# Ji Won "Jenn" Oh

Department of Communication, Seoul National University 1 Gwanak-ro, Gwanak-gu, Seoul, South Korea ohjiwon@snu.ac.kr

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests lie at the intersection of cultural studies and media studies, with an emphasis on globalization and identity. In particular, I am interested in social activism and identity-building processes of historically marginalized groups within emerging virtual media landscapes. My methodological interests are interdisciplinary, having experience with qualitative and visual methods, multimodality, focus group interviews, and big data analysis.

Keywords Popular culture, race, civic engagement, fandom, virtual experiences, media industries

## **EDUCATION**

## 2017 - 2021 Seoul National University

M.A. in Communication

Thesis Cringe Culture, Boundary-Policing, and Hybridity in Transnational K-pop Fandom

# 2012 - 2016 New York University

B.S. in Media, Culture, and Communication, *magna cum laude with Honors* Minor in Studio Art

Thesis Eating Kimchi: Nostalgia, Migration, and Identity in Korean Cuisine

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

### 2020 Research Associate

Impact of Netflix Content on the Enhancement of Consumer Preference for Korean Culture and the Korean Wave. Project supported by Netflix Korea. (PI: Seok-Kyeong Hong)

### 2018 - 2020 Research Assistant

Transnational Convergene of East Asian Pop Culure. Project supported by Seoul National University Asia Center. (PI: Seok-Kyeong Hong)

## 2018 Research Assistant

Transnational Fandom of BTS and Transmedia Storytelling. Project supported by Big Hit Entertainment. (PI: Seok-Kyeong Hong)

#### **CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS**

- May 2021 Hong, S., Ahn, H., Seo, K., Shin, J. & **Oh, J.** Does Netflix Hinder Cultural Diversity?: An Analysis of Global Top 10 Rankings on Netflix. Presented at the Korean Society of Journalism & Communication Studies Annual Spring Conference. Virtual.
- Mar 2021 Ahn, H. Shin, J., Seo, K., **Oh, J.** & Hong, S. *How Netflix Changes Cultural Diversity: An Analysis of Global Top 10 Rankings on Netflix.* Presented at Emerging Scholars Forum IV, BK21 FOUR Free & Responsible AI Media Group at Seoul National University. Virtual.
- Nov 2019 **Oh, Ji Won.** Virtual Celebrities, Storytelling, and Spectacle: Comparing Hatsune Miku and Lil Miquela. Presented at News, Information, and Media in the Post-Truth Era, SNU-UT-NCCU Joint Symposium. Seoul, South Korea.

### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

# **Teaching Assistant**

Fall 2019	College Writing for the Social Sciences Faculty of Liberal Education, Seoul National University
Fall 2019	Speech and Debate Faculty of Liberal Education, Seoul National University
Fall 2019	Methods in Korean Studies (Virtual e-School Class funded by Korea Foundation) University of Paris & Seoul National University
Spring 2019	Speech and Debate Faculty of Liberal Education, Seoul National University
Winter 2018	Popular Culture and Media in South Korea (Virtual e-School Class funded by Korea Foundation) University of Bordeaux & Seoul National University
Fall 2018	Methods in Korean Studies (Virtual e-School Class funded by Korea Foundation)

Paris Diderot University & Seoul National University

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Feb 2021- Administrative Assistant

Department of Communication, Seoul National University

Feb 2020 - Aug 2020 Editorial Assistant

Journal of Communication Research, Seoul National University

Aug 2016 - Jan 2016 **Disney College Program** 

Walt Disney Parks & Resorts, Orlando, FL

## **HONORS & AWARDS**

May 2016 Founder's Day Award, New York University

Fall 2014 - Spring 2015 Dean's List for Academic Year, New York University

Spring 2013 Dean's List, New York University

## **ADDITIONAL TRAINING**

2018 Qualitative Methods and Oral History Research, Korea Social Science Data

Archive (KOSSDA), South Korea